Hello, today we will tell you about the top six best
health insurance plans of 2024.
Before starting the video, one
important thing is that if you have not yet subscribed to our channel, then
subscribe so that
you get the right information at the right time.
And now I would like to
introduce myself. My name is
Kajal. I keep giving you updates related to health and life insurance
through this channel
and
also give you advice on every problem related to insurance.
Our team has 12
years of experience in the insurance industry and we
also provide consultancy related to claims. Let's
start today's video, friends.
Later in the video, we will tell you about the six best
plans. We will also learn
what is the ICR ratio of these plans, that is, how many claims the
company has given to the people. For
example, you paid a premium of ₹1 to the company
and out of that the company gave you a
claim of ₹1, this means that the ICR
of that company will be 75, plan wise, we will
tell you that later in this video and secondly, we will tell
you about the best features and  We
will also tell you about the benefits so that it becomes
easy for you to know
which plan will be best for you as per your needs.
First of all, we will talk
about the ICR ratio of the plans. What is the
ICR ratio of each company? The
first best plan is Niva Company's
Spire Plan and Niva B Company's AAA
ratio is
54.0. The second best plan is Star Company's
Star Ashor Plan and Star Company's AAA
ratio is 65. Now the next plan is Care
Supreme Plan and Care Company's AAA ratio is
53.8.2. Now the next plan is Aditya
Birla Company's Active Care Plan and
Aditya Birla Company's ICI ratio is
64.6. The next best plan is hdfcergo.com with
94. Out of the companies we have suggested to you so far,
hdfcergo.com has the highest claims.
So, the one with the
Bit Lock the Clock scheme locks your premium
until you make a claim.
You will get maternity coverage after nine
months. Borderless coverage is provided to you.  In
which you can get treatment anywhere over the world.
Now if you want instant cover,
for example, for diabetes, then for that
you will get Smart Health Rider available in Aspire plan.
Apart from this,
you get Booster Plus benefit. This means that if
you do not make a claim, then your sum assured can
go up to 10x. Talking about ICICI Lombard,
you have higher sum insurance
options available in it and
you also get global cover in this plan.
Talking about Star Ashor, this plan has a high
maximum entry age of 75 years and
you also get maternity coverage. Now there is no maximum
entry age limit in Care Supreme plan.
Senior citizens can also take this plan.
You will get instant cover and
you also get Super NCB cover. Now
in Aditya Birla plan, your chronic diseases will be covered
from day one, for example, if
you have any chronic disease related to BP,
kidney, heart stroke, then there will be no waiting period for their treatment.
If you have any of these or
any of the chronic diseases listed in the policy, then  This plan is
for you. Next, there is no maximum entry age.
In the Active One plan,
you get Super Graded Rs. 500 per plan which functions similarly like
No Claim Bonus. Now let's talk
about the entry age. In ADAC Optima Secure and
VAPA Expire plan, the minimum
entry age is 18 years and the maximum entry
age is 65 years. In Care Supreme Plan and
Aditya Birla Active One plan, the minimum
age is 18 years and there is no maximum age limit. In
ICICI Lombard Max
Protect plan, the minimum age is 6 years to 65
years and in Star Assure plan, the minimum age is 18
years and the maximum age is 75 years. Now let's talk about
room rent eligibility. There is
no capping on room rent in Optimus Secure Aspire Plan, Supreme Plan and Active One plan. In the rest of the Max
Protect plan, you can take any room except for the
Accept Such Category and Star
Assure plan, there is a limit on room rent.
Talking about the short term, Optimus  The
Secure plan has a sum assured of 5 lakh to 2 crores. The
Aspire plan has 3 lakh to 1 crores. The
Max Protect plan has 50 lakh to 10
crores and Limited. The Ashor plan has 5
lakh to 2 crores. The Care plan has 5 lakh
to 1 crore and the Active One plan has 5
lakh to 1 crore. The policy term of all the plans will be
one, two and three years. Now we will talk about the
bonuses available in these plans, which
you get in different ways in all the plans. We will
learn about them. First of all, we will talk about the
Optimus Secure plan, in this
you get Secure Benefit, in which
you get 2x coverage from day one. Whereas
if you have taken a Super Par Secure policy, then
you get 3x coverage from day one. Now
your Plus Benefit comes on top of that, in
which your sum assured of 50 will be added
next year and 50 par next to next
year. For example, if the policy is of 10 lakhs, then
it will become 20 lakhs in 2 years and
in the third year your Secure Benefit  If the benefit is also
added, then your policy will become worth Rs 30 lakh.
Now let's talk about the Bopa Aspire
plan. Here you get a booster
benefit. It means that the summation shot that you are not using will be carried forward to the
next year. The
policy of Rs 10 lakh will become Rs
20 lakh next year and then Rs 30
lakh. Please note that age
restrictions will be imposed on this
according to the age at which you are entering and this
maximum benefit will go up to 10x. Now
moving to the next plan,
in the ICICI Max Protect plan,
you get a guaranteed no-claim bonus at Rs 20
and this will not be reduced even if you make a
claim in the future, then this maximum
goes up to 100%. Now in the next plan, Star
Health Assure, you will get a bonus at Rs 25
in every claim-free year, which will
go up to a maximum of 100%. In Care Supreme, it is at Rs 50 and the
maximum is 100% and even if there is a claim in the future,
this will not be reduced.
Aditya Billa  In Active One, you will get 100% bonus
in a claim-free year, which will go up to a
maximum of Rs 500. And you
get this in the Vital plan. Your sum assured is
increased here.
Now, in all these plans, you get covered
Day Care Hospitalization, Domise
Hospitalization, AYUSH Hospitalization up to
sum assured. Now let's talk about refill benefit, that is,
when your sum assured gets exhausted, the
company refills your sum assured, that is,
gives you more sum assured
without charging any extra premium.
And yes, in every plan, it is known by different names,
like Restore
Benefit. So, let's find out how much refill benefit you
get.
In the Optimum Secure plan, it
is available to you once in a year. And here you also get the
option to choose it for unlimited times.
For example, if your
sum assured of Rs 10 lakh gets exhausted, then it will be
filled again and again for unlimited times.
If you choose unlimited sum assured,
Only when you opt for the Restore Rider policy, the Va
Bappa plan now has Reshot Plus.
This is triggered on the first claim and continues for life.
Similarly, the ICICI Max
Protect plan also offers unlimited
refill benefits,
which you can use for any business. The
Star Ashor plan offers 100% refill
benefit for unlimited times. The
Care Supreme plan also offers unlimited refill benefits for unlimited
times and can be
used for unrelated and same illnesses. The
Active One plan offers
unlimited restoration benefits, which can be
used for any illness.
Emergency road ambulance and
air ambulance are covered. The Optimal
Secure Aspire plan
covers age per actuals. The Max Protect plan covers up
to 100% of the sum assured and a maximum of 100%. The Ashor plan also
offers age per actuals.  In the Care Supreme plan,
you are covered up to Rs 10,000 in a plan up to Rs 15 lakh,
whereas in the Active One plan, you are
covered up to the sum assured ambulance.
Talking about air ambulance,
you are covered up to Rs 5 lakh in the Optimum Secure plan. You are covered up to Rs 5 lakh on the
Aspire plan.
In the Max Protect plan,
you will not be covered for air ambulance on choosing the Classic plan.
And in the premium variant, you
get an inbuilt air ambulance. In the Star Usher
plan, you are covered up to Rs 10 lakh of the sum assured.
In the Supreme plan, you are covered up to Rs 5 lakh
in the Active One plan.
In the Complements Secure plan, you will be covered up to a maximum of Rs
15,000 once in a year. In the Aspire plan,
you will be covered up to Rs 15,000 on the age assured actuals. In the Max Product
plan, you are covered only in the premium plan.
In the Star Usher plan, the individual
plan has a cover tax of Rs 1500 to Rs 8,000,
whereas in the floater plan,
you are covered up to Rs 15,000
in the policy.
All your insured members get these tests free of cost.
You can also get the listed tests done in the Active One plan, that too on a cashless basis.
Now let's talk about wellness benefits, that is,
if you remain healthy, take care of your health
and stay fit, then this
policy offers you some discounts. Let's
learn about them. In the Aspire plan,
you
get wellness benefits once in a policy year on a cashless basis up
to Rs 10,000. In the Star Asher plan also, you get a
discount of 20% in the Star Wellness Program.
In the Care Supreme plan, you
get wellness benefits up to 30%
and in the Active plan, you get health returns
up to 100%. However,
you do not get wellness benefits in the Optima Secure and Max Protect plans.
Now let's talk
about pre- and post-hospitalization expenses, that is, the
expenses before admission to the hospital and the
expenses after discharge. For
how many days do these plans cover?
In all the plans, pre-hospitalization
expenses cover your 60%.
Your pre-hospitalization expenses are
covered for up to 180 days only
in Active One plan. Your pre-hospitalization
expenses are covered for 90 days and post-hospitalization expenses for up to 180 days.
You get e-consultation benefit.
Your 51 listed critical illnesses are covered in Optimal Secure plan.
Your unlimited illnesses are covered in Aspire and Max Protect plans.
And in Active One plan,
you do not get e-consultation benefit. Your
non-payable items are covered.
You get inbuilt cover in Optimal Secure plan.
You get
Safeguard and Safeguard Plus benefit in Aspire plan.
You are covered up to this sum in Max Protect plan.
On choosing premium variant, your non-payable items are covered in Star Ashor plan.
These expenses are covered in Rider Claim Shield in Care Supreme plan. These
expenses are covered
inbuilt in Claim Protect in Active One plan.
Now OPD cover
You get OPD cover in these plans. In the rest of the Star
Assure and Active One plans, you do
not get OPD cover. Now, in the Max Protect plan,
you will get zone-based CO payment.
In other plans, you will not get CO payment.
If you get deducted options, then deductible options are
available in the Optimus Secure plan. In the Aspire plan,
you get deductible options up to Rs 1 lakh.
In the Star Assured plan,
you get deductible options up to Rs 20 lakh. And
in the Max Protect Care Supreme and Active One plans, deductible options are
not available. Now let's talk about
maternity expenses.
In the Optimus Secure plan, your maternity
expenses are not covered.
In the Aspire plan, your maternity expenses are covered under the Miracle Benefit, in
which your deliveries, adoption, surrogacy and
IVF are covered. In ICICI and
Max Protect, you do
not get maternity expenses cover. In the Star Assure plan,
you do not get maternity expenses.
Newborn baby and IPF are covered. You
are covered in Care Supreme and Aditya Billa also.
Maternity is not covered in Care Supreme and Aditya Billa. Now let's talk about
global coverage. Friends,
global cover is not available in hdfcergo.com One plan.
Now we will talk
about the optional riders that you
get in these plans. It means if you
want additional benefits in your plan, then you
can take this rider within the policy by
paying an additional premium. In ADAC Optima
Secure plan, you get optional riders, in
which the first one is Unlimited
Restore Benefit, Hospital Cash Benefit and
Critical Illness Benefit. In Aspire plan,
you get riders like Cash Bag, Borderless Future Ready, Fast
Forward
Safeguard Plus, Hospital Daily Cash Benefit,
Personal Accident Cover, Smart Health Plus
and Well Consult OPD Writer. Now, you
also get riders in III company's Max Protect plan, in
which the
option of pre-registration is not available. Whereas
in Care Supreme plan, you have the option of rider in
which you get NCB
Super.  Riders Pre-existing Disease Waiting
Period Modification Rider Annual Health
Checkup Rider Instant Cover Claim Shield &
Care OPD Rider Next, you get an
inbuilt Chronic Care Rider in the Active One plan,
which covers your pre-existing diseases from
day one. Now, let's talk about the
waiting period of these plans. The initial
waiting period for all these plans is 30
days. For specific illnesses, you have a
waiting period of 2 years. If we
talk about the waiting period for pre-existing diseases,
it differs in all the plans.
In the Optimus Secure plan, you have a waiting period of 3 years.
For treatment related to pre-existing diseases, if you
choose the Gold Plus plan in the Niva Bupa Aspire plan, you will have a waiting
period of 4 years. If you choose the Diamond Platinum and
Titanium plans, you will have a
waiting period of 3 years. Talking about the Max Protect plan,
in this you get the option to reduce your pre-
existing disease waiting period. Instead of
4 years,
you can reduce the waiting period to 2 years.  You can expect a
36-month waiting period for the Star Assur plan
if you pay a 2-year premium in one go. A
30-month waiting
period if you pay a 3-year premium in
one go. The Supreme
plan offers a 48-month waiting period,
and the Active One plan offers a 3-
year waiting period for pre-existing
disease-related treatment.
You can see the premium details of these plans
on your screen. So friends,
we have provided complete information
about the best health insurance plans of 2021. Now
you
can choose the best plan according to your requirements. So friends, that's all for
today's video. We hope
you found the information in this video really
useful. We will continue to
bring you important information related to health and life insurance. All those who are
connected with us, please continue
with us on this journey. If you are
new to our channel, please
subscribe to our channel.
Thank you very much for staying with us till the end of this video.